Guide to the Sarah G. Jacobson Papers MSS.157
Fales Library and Special Collections
Sarah G. Jacobson Papers
1953-2012
Fales Library and Special Collections
Jacobson, Sarah
MSS.157
54.3 Linear Feet in 30 record cartons, 5 flat boxes, 2 manuscript boxes and 5 custom containers.
14 VHS
9 DVDs
30 MiniDV
5 CD-ROM
4 DAT
1 audiocassette
4.22 Gigabytes in 6057 computer files
1 film reels
10 DVD-R
Sarah Jacobson was born in Norwalk, Connecticut in 1971. Her family eventually moved to Edina, Minnesota, where Jacobson graduated from high school. As a teenager, Sarah Jacobson was drawn to the independent film and music scene in Minneapolis. She attended the San Francisco Art Institute where she met her mentor, George Kuchar. While still in film school, Sarah Jacobson wrote, produced and directed her first films including, The Adventures of Sweet Miss: The Disco Years and I Was A Teenage Serial Killer. Shortly after graduating from College, Jacobson, wrote, directed and produced her first feature-length film, Mary Jane's Not A Virgin Anymore, which screened internationally. The Sarah Jacobson Papers include production materials from her independent film projects, freelance writing, activism work, teaching and commercial work. Material types include film production materials, writing, clippings, audio-cassettes, video recordings, films, flyers, fanzines and artifacts.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Ruth Jacobson in 2005; additional accretions were donated in 2008 and 2018. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2004.157, 2008.157, and 2018.079.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Biographical Note
Sarah Jacobson was born in Norwalk, Connecticut in 1971. Her family moved to Edina, Minnesota, where Jacobson graduated from high school. As a teenager, Sarah Jacobson was drawn to the independent film and music scene in Minneapolis. After graduating from Edina High School in 1989, Sarah Jacobson attended Bard College for her freshman year. Dissatisfied with Bard, Jacobson moved to San Francisco to attend the San Francisco Art Institute where she met her mentor, George Kuchar.
While still in film school, Sarah Jacobson wrote, produced and directed her first films including, The Adventures of Sweet Miss: The Disco Years and I Was A Teenage Serial Killer. Shortly after graduating from college, Jacobson, wrote, directed and produced her first feature-length film, Mary Jane's Not A Virgin Anymore, which screened internationally. Sarah Jacobson was a firm believer in "DIY" or the "Do It Yourself" method of filmmaking. With her mother, Ruth Jacobson, she established her own production company, Station Wagon Productions, to handle the distribution of her film projects in keeping with the "DIY" manifesto. Jacobson also did some commercial work for VH1, Oxygen Media and is known to have shot at least one music video for the British punk band Fluffy. Sarah Jacobson's influences include filmakers George Kuchar, Jim Jarmusch, Susan Seidelman, John Hughes, Tamra Davis, Alison Anders, and the musical groups Babes In Toyland, Heavens to Betsy, L7 and Gas Huffer.
In addition to her film projects, Jacobson did freelance writing for several publications including YM,Sassy,Film Threat,Punk Planet and Filth. Sarah Jacobson also considered herself an activist, not only through her own film work and teaching but through her involvement with 50/50, a feminist collective that sought to attain gender equality in the film and televison industry.
Sarah Jacobson passed away on February 13th, 2004 due to uterine cancer. Before her death, Jacobson was developing Sleaze, a film chronicling the life of a 15-year-old girl who hooks up with an all-girl rock band touring Missoula, Montana. Sleaze appears to be inspired by the film, Ladies and Gentlemen the Fabulous Stains (Written by Nancy Dowd and Directed by Lou Alder) for which Jacobson made a short documentary. Her last films included a documentary about her 10-year high school reunion and True Love Mohawk, documenting Jacobson and her boyfriend, Aaron Zisman giving each other mohawks.
Filmography
I Was A Teenage Serial Killer (1993)
Mary Jane's Not A Virgin Anymore (1997)
The Making of Ladies and Gentlemen, The Fabulous Stains (2000)
Other Film and Video Works
Sweet Miss: the Disco Years, (1988) (http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KRCjfvgWk5A)
Road Trip, or What I Learned in a Buick Station Wagon, (1991) (http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pLj0ot1Oa_s)
Fluffy (Music Video), (undated) (http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XDz_DUchZ80)
Man or Astroman? "Spferic Waves", (1996) (http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ps32wFxDY94)
Scope and Contents
The Sarah G. Jacobson Papers include production materials from her independent film projects, freelance writing, activism work, teaching and commercial work. Material types include film production materials, writing, clippings, audio-cassettes, video recordings, films, flyers, fanzines and artifacts. The bulk of the collection relates to Jacobson's professional career, primarily the production of her films Mary Jane's Not A Virgin Anymore and I Was A Teenage Serial Killer. However, the collection also contains material related to a number of Jacobson's smaller film projects such as The Adventures of Sweet Miss: The Disco Years, Sleaze, a music video for the british punk band, Fluffy, and a documentary film about the making of Lou Alder's feature, Ladies and Gentlemen, The Fabulous Stains.
In addition to film projects, the collection contains clippings, audio recordings and notes relating to Jacobson's work with VH1, Oxygen Media, and 50/50 Women Filmmaker's Summit (now called MoviesByWomen.com). Jacobson's freelance writing dates back to at least 1992 when she started writing for independent fanzines and underground film and music publications such as Filth and Film Threat. Jacobson also wrote for more commercial publications such as Sassy and YM
Sarah Jacobson collected a variety of films on tape, news clippings, and fanzines from others that are organized according to artist/ filmmaker or subject. Many of the subjects represented in this portion of the collection relate to Jacobson's professional and personal social circle. Some materials come from filmakers Jacobson was in contact with or inspired by such as Tamra Davis, Allison Anders and her mentor and teacher George Kuchar. Other collection materials include clippings about 1990s pop-culture phenomena, such as the musical bands Hole and Nirvana and television personalities Roseanne and Shannen Doherty.
The 2008 accretion consists of a larger group of material related to the original accession, specifically items related to Jacobson's professional contributions to film and journalism. In addition, this accretion includes a new series consisting of items related to Jacobson's student life, including classwork and notebooks ranging from her elementary to collegiate education.
The 2018 accretion contains personal notebooks, correspondence, and writing from 1987 to 2012, as well as her published work on modern film. Also included are full-length digital recordings of her shorts, including I Was A Teenage Serial Killer, The Adventures of Sweet Miss: The Disco Years, and High School Reunion. Photography from multiple Sundance Film Festivals and the production of Mary Jane's Not A Virgin Anymore are present as well.
Arrangement
The Sarah G. Jacobson Papers are arranged chronologically by project. In some cases materials are arranged alphabetically. Every attempt was made to preserve the original order of the material. The collection is organized into eleven main series, followed by oversize materials and materials from the 2008 accretion.
The 2018 accretion has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Series I: I Was a Teenage Serial Killer
Series II: Mary Jane's Not A Virgin Anymore
Series III: The Stains Documentary
Series IV: Professional Projects
Series V: Miscellaneous Media Originals
Series VI: Other Authors
Series VII: Printed Material
Series VIII: Teaching Materials
Series IX: Nostalgia, Neat Things
Series X: Miscellaneous
Series XI: Media Access Copies
Oversize - Series I.B: I Was a Teenage Serial Killer - Production Materials
Oversize - Series II.A: Mary Jane's Not A Virgin Anymore - Production Materials
Oversize - Series II.B: Mary Jane's Not A Virgin Anymore - Distribution and Public Relations
Oversize - Series IV.D: Professional Projects - Hardcorn
Oversize - Series IX: Nostalgia, Neat Things
Oversize - Series X: Miscellaneous
Accretion 2008 - Series I: I Was a Teenage Serial Killer
Accretion 2008 - Series II: Mary Jane's Not A Virgin Anymore
Accretion 2008 - Series III: The Stains Documentary
Accretion 2008 - Series IV: Professional Projects
Accretion 2008 - Series V: Miscellaneous Media Originals
Accretion 2008 - Series VII: Printed Material
Accretion 2008 - Series VIII: Teaching Materials
Accretion 2008 - Series X: Miscellaneous
Accretion 2008 - Series XII: Student Materials
Accretion 2008 - Oversize - Series IV: Professional Projects
Accretion 2008 - Oversize - Series X: Miscellaneous
Accretion 2008 - Oversize - Series XII: Student Materials
Accretion 2018 - Series XIII.
Separated Material
Some materials have been separated and moved to the Fales Downtown Book Collection and to the General Stacks. Records for these items can also be retrieved through a "related name" search in Bobcat, NYU's online catalog.
Materials moved into the Fales Downtown Book Collection
A
Ain't Nothin' Like Fuckin' Moonshine!, #10, Summer 1995.
Anonymous Boy, # 2, 3, 4, 7, 8.
A Bag of Sand, # 7.
B
Baggie, Petey-Boy, Hate, # 1, 2, 3, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30.
A Bag of Sand, # 7.
B.B. Gun, #5, 2001.
Beer Frame: The Journal of Inconspicuous Consumption, # 5, 7, 8, 9, 10.
Belile, Liz, ed. Gynomite: Fearless, Feminist Porn. New Orleans: New Mouth From the Dirty South, 2000.
Ben Is Dead, No. 16/17, 18, 19, 20/21, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 30, 1991-1998.
Besmirched, 2 issues.
Biggs, Brian. Frederick and Eloise: A Love Story. FantaGraphic Books.
Bitch: Feminist Response to Pop Culture, vol. 1, no. 2; vol. 1, no. 3, 1996; vol. 2, no. 3, 1997; vol. 3, no. 1, 1998; vol. 3, no. 2, 1998; vol. 3, no. 3, 1998; vol. 4, no. 1 (#10), 1999; #12, 2000.
Bitches, Bimbos and Ballbreakers: The Guerilla Girls' Guide to Female Stereotypes. New York: Penguin Books, 2003.
Blowdryer, Jennifer. White Trash Debutante. New York: Galhattan Press, 1997.
Blush, Steven. American Hardcore. Los Angeles: Feral House, 2001.
Broken Spoke, vol. 1, no. 2, August 27, 1993.
Brutarian, no. 24, 1998.
Bunnyhop, no. 7, 1996.
Burn collector, # 11.
Bust, Fall/Winter 1993; Winter/Spring 1995; Summer/Fall 1995; Spring/Summer 1996; Fall/Winter 1996; Spring/Summer 1997; Winter/Spring 1998; Summer/Fall 1998; Spring 1999; Fall 1999; Spring 2000; Fall 2000; Winter 2000; Spring 2001; Summer 2001; Spring 2002; Summer 2002; Fall 2002; Winter 2002; Fall 2003; Winter 2003; Spring 2003; Summer 2003.
C
Cake, vol. 11, issue 22, Spring 1994.
Carbon 14, no. 9, 12, 14, 15, 16, 17.
Cashiers du Cinemart, # 5, 6, 7, 9, 10.
Celluloid/All, # 2, 5.
Cine-cyde, # 1.
Cinelust, # 2.
ChinMusic, vol. 1, no. 1; vol. 1, no. 2.
Chunklet, # 15.
Cliff Notes on Man or Astroman? (zine), n.d.
Cole, Joe. Planet Joe. Los Angeles: 2.13.61 Publications, 1992.
Cool Beans!, # 5, 6, 7, 8, 9 (Uncool Beans), 10, 11, 12, 14.
Crimewave U.S.A., # 9, 10, 11, 13.
D
Dangerous Pussy, # 2, 3.
Danzine, # 16, 17.
Darcy, Dame. Meat Cake. # 2, 5.
Deep Girl, # 5, Summer 1995.
Detroit! Murder City Comix, # 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
Die Evan Dando, Die, n.d.
Dirt, # 1, 2, 3, 4.
Dishwasher, # 9, 13, 14, 15.
D.I.Y.: We Created It, Let's Take It Over, n.d.
Diva, Graphics and Stories, 1993.
Doucet, Julie. Purty Plotte. # 9, 10, 12.
Doucet, Julie. Dirty Plotte. # 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
E
Clowes, Daniel. Eightball. # 7, 8, 10, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22.
8-Track Mind Magazine, # 88, 90, 91, 93, 94, 95, 96, 100.
Essential Cinema: Journal of Independent Film, vol. 1, no. 1, Fall 1993 (2 copies).
EYE, # 14, 15, 20, 21, 22.
F
Fabula, vol. 3, no. 2; vol. 3, no. 3; vol. 3, no. 4; vol. 4, no. 1; vol. 4, no. 2.
Factsheet Five: Zine Publisher's Resource Guide, n.d.
Femme flicke, # 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7.
The Film Gofer's Digest, # 2.
Film Threat, # 10, 12, 14, 15, 16, 18, 19, 20, 21.
Film Threat Video Guide, # 2, 5, 7, 8, 10 (2 copies), 11, 12, 13 (2 copies), 14.
Films in Review, January/February 1997.
Filth, # 11, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24.
The Filth and the Fury, # 5.
Flat Bed, # 4.
Fleener, Mary. Slutburger. #5, July 1995.
Fleener, # 1, 1996.
Fringecore, # 1.
G
Gearhead, # 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 7.
Genetic Disorder, # 14, 15.
George, Nelson. Buppies, B-Boys, Baps and Bohos: Notes on Post-soul Black Culture. New York: HarperCollins Publishers, 1992.
Giant Robot, # 8, 1997.
Girl Germs, # 5.
Girlhero, # 1, 2, 4, 5, 6.
Girl's Life Magazine, # 2.
Girlyhead, # 1, 2 (2 copies), 3, 4.
Grand Royal, # 1, 2, 3, 4, 6.
Gregory, Roberta. Naughty Bits. # 4, 6.
H
Handsome, # 1, 2, 3.
Hard Corn, # 1, 2.
Hard Rock Comics, 4 issues.
Heavy Dog Spit, # 1.
Heeb, vol. 1, no. 1, Winter 2002.
Heinous, # 5, September 1998.
Hessian Obsession, # 1, 2.
Hip Mama, # 12, 14, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20.
Hit It or Quit It, # 9, 12, 13, 14, 15.
Homopunk World, #1; # 2, Summer 1999; # 3, Summer 2000.
I
I (heart) Amy Carter, # 3, 4, 5.
Infiltration, # 7, 8.
Inkling, # 2.
Interrobang?!, # 3, Winter 1996/1997.
Insubordinator Magazine, issue 5, vol. 1.
J
Jacobs, Greg. Hell on Wheels: A Tour Stories Compilation. San Diego: Rockpress Publishing, 1994.
Johnson, Denis. Jesus' Son. New York: HarperPerennial, 1983.
Juxtapoz, vol. 1, no. 1, Winter 1994; vol. 1, no. 2, Spring 1995; vol. 1, no. 3, Summer 1995; vol. 2, no. 1, Winter 1995; vol. 2, no. 3, Summer 1996; vol. 2, no. 4, Fall 1996; vol. 3, no. 1, Winter 1996; vol. 2, no. 3, Summer 1996; vol. 2, no. 4, Fall 1996; vol. 3, no. 1, Winter 1996; vol. 3, no. 3, Summer 1997; vol. 5, no. 3, Fall 1998 (Issue#16), vol. 6, no. 2, March/April 1999 (Issue#19).
K
KGB, Winter 1996.
Kino Gun, # 2.
Kitty Magik, # 6, October 2001.
L
The Last Prom: eclectic esoterica for a better tomorrow, # 2, 1993.
Lumpen, vol. 5, no. 4, August 1996.
M
Matik, Wendy-O. So Much for Passion. San Francisco: manic d press, 1990.
Matik, Wendy-O. She Knew Better. San Francisco: manic d press, 1992.
Mazel-Tov Cocktail (A.K.A. Jew-Core), # 1, June 1995.
McJob, # 2, 3, 4.
Mean, # 6, 7, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, May/June 2000, July/August/2000.
Mekas, Jonas. I Had Nowhere to Go. New York: Black Thistle Press, 1991.
Metasex, 2 issues.
MicroFilm, March 1999.
The Moocher's Periodical, # 10, March 1993.
Mommy and I Are One, # 6, 7(Summer/Fall 1999).
MondoCine, vol. 1, no. 1, Summer 1996; vol. 1, no. 2, Fall 1996; vol. 1, no. 3, Spring 1997.
Motorbooty, # 2, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, Spring 1988 - Spring 1999.
Mudflap, # 4, 5, 6.
Multiball, #16, #20, 1999-2000.
Multiball, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 12.
Murder Can Be Fun, # 1, 5, 9/10, 13, 17, 18.
Murder Can Be Fun (comic book), # 1, February 1996.
N
Nuts to You, vol. 2, no. 7.
O
On the Make, # 2, 1997.
Tomine, Adrian. Optic Nerve. # 1, 4, 5.
P
Panter, Nicole, ed. Unnatural Disasters: Recent Writings from the Golden State. San Diego: Incommunicado Press, 1996.
Peops, 2002.
The Poison Ivy League, # 2, Winter 2000.
Plotz, 8, 10, 11, 12, 13, 16.
Polvo, #1, 1997.
Pop Boffin, #5.
Popgirls, # 1, 2.
Princess, #4, June 1998.
Prison Life, September-October 1995, March-April 1996.
Private Catholic, # 4.
The Probe, No. 5, 6, 7, 8.
Proof, # 1.
Q
Queen of the Universe, # 2, 3, 4.
R
Random Letters to Ransom Girls, n.d.
Read, vol. 4, no. 17, 2000.
Res the Magazine of Digital Filmmaking, Preview Issue.
Retard Riot, # 1.
Riot Ukes (newsletter), 3 issues.
Rivera, Sandra Garcia. Divination of the Mistress. New York: Sandra Garcia Rivera, 1999.
Rocktober, # 16, 20, 21, 22, 23, 28.
Rockrgrl, #16, 22-23.
Rock 'N' Roll Comics, 6 issues.
Rollerderby, # 14, 15, 17, 18, 19, 21, 22, 23, 24.
Rube Waddell's Book of Junkyard Wisdom, n.d.
S
Sassy, # 39, 43, 44, 46, 47, 48, 50, 51, 52, 53, 54, 55, 56, 57, 58, 59, 60, 61, 62, 63, 64, 65, 66, 67, 68, 69, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77, 78, 79, 80.
Scam, # 1, 2, 3, 4.
The scaredy-cat stalker, # 2, 3, 4, 7.
Screaming Kat, # 1, September 1995; #2, March 1996; # 3, April 1997.
Schrag, Ariel. Definition. Berkeley, CA: 08206 Comics, 1996.
Schrag, Ariel. Awkward. 1995.
Scram, # 3, 5, 6, 7, 8.
S.F.I.S.S., # 3.
Shock Cinema, # 7, 8, 9, 11, 12, 13, 14.
Sight Unseen, #1, Summer 1999.
Sinister, Bucky. Twelve Bowls of Glass. San Francisco: manic d press, 1990.
Siren, # 1, 2, 3.
Skuld's Hag Rag, # 7, Spring 2001.
Slap, vol. 1, no. 1, April 1992; vol. 1, no. 2, May 1992.
Bill Landis' Sleazoid Express, Spring 1999.
Slop hut, # 1, 2.
Smite, # 3.
Snak Fud Fanzine, # 8, Winter 1995.
Socially Fucking Retarded.
Soup, 1997.
Spiral Scratch, vol. 2, issue 4, November 1990.
Static, #1, Summer 1996; #2, Winter 1996.
Star Wars Generation, # 1.
Stay Free, # 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, Marketing to Kids Issue, Spring 1997 - Spring 2002.
Stevenson, Jack. Addicted: The Myth and Menace of Drugs in Film. London: Creation Books, 1999.
Stevenson, Jack. Desperate Vision: Camp America. London: Creation Books, 1996.
SubCulture Music Newsletter, #2:11.
Sub-Vision, # 1.
Suck Don't Blow.
Summersault, 1995.
Sweet, Lucy. Unskinny. London: Quartet Books, 1997.
T
Teenage Gang Debs, # 2, 3, 4, 5, March 1990 - May 1993.
Teen Fag Magazine, # 4, 6.
Thrift Score, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14.
Tommy, # 6, 8, 9.
The Trouble With Normal, # 40, 41.
V
Vague, Spring 1997.
Venus, Summer 2000, Winter 2001, Spring 2002.
Violin Outbreak, # 8, 11, 13, 14, 15.
W
Wagons of Steel Magazine, # 8, 9, 11.
Y
yak'uz'a, #9, 1997.
Yeah!, # 1, 2, 3, 4.
Young Lust, # 8, 1993.
Your Flesh, #16, Summer 1989.
Z
ZAPRUDER headSNAP, # 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13.
Zedd, Nick. Totem of the Depraved. Los Angeles: 2.13.61 Publications, 1996.
Materials moved into the General Stacks
A
Alcoholics Anonymous. New York: Alcoholics Anonymous World Services, 2000.
Anger, Kenneth. Kenneth Anger's Hollywood Babylon. New York: Dell Books, 1975.
Anger, Kenneth. Kenneth Anger's Hollywood Babylon II. New York, Plume Books, 1984.
Archie's Girls: Betty and Veronica, # 312.
Archie's Joke Book, # 280, 507.
Arnold, Gina. Route 666: On the Road to Nirvana. New York: St. Martin's Press, 1993.
Aronson, Linda. Screenwriting Updated: New (and Conventional) Ways of Writing for the Screen. Los Angeles: Silman-James Press, 2000.
B
Ball, William. A Sense of Direction: Some Observations on the Art of Directing. New York: Drama Publishers, 1984.
Barbach, Lonnie Garfield. For Yourself: The Fulfillment of Female Sexuality. New York: Signet Books, 1976.
Barrie, James M. Peter Pan. New York: Grosset and Dunlap, Inc., 1965.
Bernstein, Jonathan. Pretty in Pink: The Golden Age of Teenage Movies. New York: St. Martin's Griffin, 1997.
Best of Stay Free 1993 - 1995, 1996.
Boetig, Donna Elizabeth. Feminine Wiles: Creative Techniques for Writing Women's Feature Stories that Sell. Clovis, CA: Quill Driver Books, 1998.
Bond, Marybeth. Gutsy Women: Travel Tips and Wisdom for the Road. San Francisco: Travelers' Tales, Inc., 1997.
Bradbury, Ray. Fahrenheit 451. New York: Ballantine Books, 1983.
Brown, Peter and Steven Gaines. The Love You Make: An Insider's Story of the Beatles. New York: Signet Books, 1984.
Brown, Peter and Steven Gaines. The Love You Make: An Insider's Story of the Beatles. New York: Signet Books, 1984.
Burgess, Anthony. A Clockwork Orange. New York: W.W. Norton and Company, 1987.
C
Campbell, Joseph. The Hero With a Thousand Faces. Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1973.
Campion, Jane. The Piano. New York: Hyperion, 1993.
Capote, Truman. Breakfast at Tiffany's. New York: Signet Books, 1961.
Carducci, Joe. Rock and the Pop Narcotic. Los Angeles: 2.13.61 Publications, 1994.
Carnegie, Dale. How to Win Friends and Influence People. New York: Pocket Books, 1998.
Carnes, Patrick. Don't Call It Love: Recovery From Sexual Addiction. New York: Bantam Books, 1991.
Carnes, Patrick. A Gentle Path Through the Twelve Steps. Center City, MN: Hazelden, 1993.
Carroll, Jim. The Basketball Diaries. New York: Penguin Books, 1987.
Carroll, Jim. Living at the Movies. New York: Penguin Books, 1981.
Chandler, Raymond. The Big Sleep. New York: Vintage Books, 1988.
Chopra, Deepak. The Seven Spiritual Laws of Success: A Practical Guide to the Fulfillment of Your Dreams. San Raphael, CA: Amber-Allen Publishing, 1994.
Clarke, Miranda. Night of a Thousand Boyfriends. San Francisco: Quirk Productions, 2003.
Cleaver, Eldridge. Soul on Ice. New York: Delta Books, 1999.
Coleman, Ray. Lennon. New York: McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1984.
Condon, Richard. The Manchurian Candidate. New York: Jove Books, 1988.
Crowe, Cameron. Conversations with Wilder. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 2001.
A Currency of Hope. Needham, MA: Debtor's Ananymous General Service Board, Inc., 1999.
D
danzine, # 13.
Dmytryk, Edward. On Film Editing. Boston: Focal Press, 1984.
drift, # 7.
Dworkin, Susan. Making Tootsie: A Film Study with Dustin Hoffman and Sydney Pollack. New York: Newmarket Press, 1983.
E
Eisler, Riane. The Chalice and the Blade. San Francisco: HarperCollins, 1988.
Elgin, Kathleen. The First Book of Mythology: Greek - Roman. New York: Franklin Watts, Inc., 1955.
Evans, Liz. Women, Sex and Rock'N"Roll in Their Own Words. San Francisco: Pandora, 1994.
F
Field, Syd. Screenplay: The Foundations of Screenwriting. New York: Dell Publishing, 1994.
Film Threat: Hollywood's Indie Voice, no. 1, January 1997; no.2, February 1997.
Film Threat: The Other Movie Magazine/Taking Hollywood by Farce/Hollywood's Voice of Treason, no. 4, 7, 8, 13, 15, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 28.
Fitzgerald, F. Scott. The Great Gatsby. New York: Collier Books, 1986.
French, Renee. The Ninth Gland. March 1997.
Fuck the Shut Up, 1999.
G
Gaer, Joseph. What the Great Religions Believe. New York: Signet Books, 1963.
Gore, Chris. The Ultimate Film Festival Survival Guide. Los Angeles: Lone Eagle Publishing, 1999.
Grey, Rudolph. Nightmare of Ecstasy: The Life and Art of Edward D. Wood, Jr. Los Angeles: Feral House, 1992.
Guide du Platz, # 14.
H
Haas, Charlie and Tim Hunter. Over the Edge. New York: Grove Press, 1979.
Hahen, Uta. Respect for Acting. New York: MacMillan Publishing Company, 1973.
Haines, Staci. The Survivor's Guide to Sex: How to Have an Empowered Sex Life After Child Sexual Abuse. San Francisco: Cleis Press, 1999.
Hammett, Dashiell. The Maltese Falcon. New York: Vintage Books, 1972.
Hastings, Betty-Ann. Betty-Ann's Helpful Household Hints, Volume I. New York: Ventura Books, 1983.
Heavy Dog Spit, 1993.
Hoeye, Michael. Time Stops for No Mouse. Portland: Terfle Books, 2001.
How Al-Anon Works for Families and Friends of Alcoholics. Virginia Beach: Al-Anon Family Group, 1995.
Huber, Cheri. The Depression Book: Depression as an Opportunity for Spiritual Growth. Murphys, CA: Keep It Simple Books, 1999.
Hurston, Zora Neale. Their Eyes Were Watching God. New York: Perennial Library, 1990.
Huxley, Aldous. Brave New World. New York: Perennial Books, 1989.
J
James, P.D. An Unsuitable Job for a Woman. New York: Warner Books, 1987.
Jancik, Wayne and Tad Lathrop. Cult Rockers. New York: Fireside Books, 1995.
K
Kael, Pauline. Pauline Kael on Jonathan Demme. Minneapolis: Walker Art Center, 1988.
Kanda, Mori. Love God: The Comic Book. n.d.
Kasl, Charlotte. If the Buddha Dated: A Handbook for Finding Love on a Spiritual Path. New York: Penguin/Arkana, 1999.
Katz, Robert. Love is Colder than Death: The Life and Times of Rainer Werner Fassbinder. New York: Random House, 1987.
Katz, Robert. Love is Colder than Death: The Life and Times of Rainer Werner Fassbinder. New York: Random House, 1987.